Guide to the Stéphane Prince Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Stéphane Prince papers
1947-1970
GEN MSS 1069
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.42
(4 boxes)
The material consists of manuscripts, typescripts, notes, date books, journals, financial records, and correspondence and subject files which document Prince's preparation of his publications Sacha Guitry hors sa légende (1959), L'Esprit français (1961), and various unpublished essays, plays, poetry and other writings on Sacha Guitry and other subjects.
Prince, Stéphane
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Pierre Beres (Drouot-Richelieu sale, Paris, 2000 Nov 29-30, lot 89) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Stéphane Prince
Stéphane Prince was a French writer, and personal secretary to the actor, playwright, and theater and film director Sacha Guitry from 1951 to 1957.
Scope and Contents
The material consists of manuscripts, typescripts, notes, date books, journals, financial records, and correspondence and subject files dating from the 1940s through the 1970s, which document Prince's preparation of his publications Sacha Guitry hors sa légende (1959), L'Esprit français (1961), and various unpublished essays, plays, poetry and other writings on Sacha Guitry and other subjects.
Arrangement
Arranged by type of material.
Authors, French -- 20th Century; Authors -- France -- 20th Century; Guitry, Sacha, 1885-1957; Prince, Stéphane
- Writings
  - Books
    - L'Esprit français, 1961-1962, undated; 5 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes manuscript and typescript drafts and notes.
    - Sacha Guitry hors sa legende, 1959, undated; 11 (Box 1)
      Includes manuscript and typescript drafts, notes, and a corrected copy of the publication. Accompanied by correspondence, writings, and notes regarding Sacha Guitry.
    - Sacha Guitry hors sa legende (continued), 1959, undated; 18 (Box 2)
  - Plays
    Includes manuscript and typescript drafts.
    - "Un beau jeaune homme" (Box 2)
    - "La chaise", undated (Box 2)
    - "Les collets montes", 1949 (Box 2)
    - "Le decor de l'envers", undated (Box 2)
    - "L'Impromtu de minuit", undated (Box 2)
    - "Le jeu de massacre", 1951 (Box 2)
    - "La lettre à Elise", 1945 (Box 2)
    - "La mythomane", 1955, 1959, undated (Box 2)
    - "L'occasion manquée", 1946 (Box 2)
    - "Paroles au vent", 1948 (Box 2)
    - "Le rocher d'Horeb", undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous drafts of plays, undated (Box 2)
    - "Impressions sur la verite," typescript by Jacques Prince, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1947-1952 (Box 2)
  - Articles, presentations, and lectures, 1947-1970; 19 (Box 3)
- Personal files
  - Address book, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Financial records, 1953-1957; 3 (Box 3)
  - Journals, 1944-1951; 3 (Box 3)
  - Datebooks, 1954-1962; 5 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence and subject files
    - Automobile, 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - Club des amis du livre, 1961-1965 (Box 4)
    - F.A.C.O.M., 1954 (Box 4)
    - Guitry, Madame, 1957-1960 (Box 4)
    - "Papiers Clélia," "Papiers Cookie" [dogs], 1954-1955 (Box 4)
    - Télévision, 1959-1960 (Box 4)
    - Valore, Lucie, 1952, 1963, undated (Box 4)